Since the beginning of time men
have roamed the Earth and are
the elements in search of
Adventure. But today there
is a new breed of Adventurer
the scientist who explores
Uncharted areas of the world not
for riches over Adventure,
but in search of answers to man's
problems of pollution and disease
such a man on such a quest
leads an ecological expedition to a primitive.
Of Latin American Fishing Community where
they uncover the Hideous
fruit of atomic radiation
in the form of a bizarre
Legend wrapped in
Terror and Written in
Blood.
Yeah, go see.
Did you get your hat?
Sampling of blood taken from these primitive people whose
main diet is seafood
fish provides
evidence that chemical changes
produced by underwater detonations of
atomic materials have
been carried by tides and currents to
all parts of the world
here is what we learned from this morning's blood sample factored
worse worse than
I expected the contamination
level and keeps Rising.
Damn it. We cannot ask these people to change their
diet. There's no chance of error. I
check it again.
Another month here isn't going to change our findings
already. These people have absorbed over a
hundred times a safe amount of
radioactive contamination the main
deities of the sea, who would you
accept a small
world, isn't it? Well, we
might as well tell Carlos will pack up and
go back to Vallejo in the morning.
I'll prepare a full report for the government
may not want to leave just yet Rick you got
there moored at sample of water. You want it for
the mouth of the river and
A lot more what would you say if I said I
had the devil in that canister, but I would
say that more time has got
a cook. I sense of humor those
local villagers aren't the only fisherman around here.
See what I got.
wait
If you've got a brain the size
now they say the octopus is supposed to be the most
intelligent species in the ocean
never seen anything like that before never.
It must be a hybrid of some sort and even a
mutation.
Let's go back to where you found. It said you with my ladies
bar. So she acted Myrick.
Neville can't weigh more than a few hours at Xerox of
kamla heavyweight. Let's not
overdramatize.
Let's concentrate on finding more where this came
from
How about a little fella you got any brothers or sisters?
Let it go once to get
somewhere.
It seems like it's waiting for a
signal.
You better get it back in there.
First thing in the morning. I'm going to take this into the research center in
Vallejo and show it to dr. Willy
navel if I went her old life. I've
got to I need some civilization
for a change. We'll keep an eye on the
shop. Well, let's bring back some
tobacco and matches lots of
matches, but we shouldn't be gone more than a day or two.
Hey the most joy joy.
We will call you number two
numero dos to distinguish you
from mr. Stein's
discovery.
Or this is seniorita.
Rick Campbell John, I'm sorry about the
short notice. That's all
right, what brings you
in business or pleasure?
You're the business Susanna's off to the beauty
parlor the
Practical female. She can prove
it. You know, we got engaged.
Okay say that I'm surprised
but you said there was something special we brought you back.
David
dead
you had a chance to study its habits
preliminary examination short of dissection,
but we did concur Rollin and
Stein and I that he was a fine
a mutation of sorts that have all the
characteristics of a human cell.
I don't agree that nowadays. We can believe all the study
Theory begins in the time that
man first crawled out of the sea
Frankie brick. I don't see any relevance
between this and your current field
Mission, but all the data we've gathered
so far John relates to see
life.
I look.
The past two years
Your Role water tests in various parts of the
world have definitely proved
something.
But this odd Little Squid
first establish any relation between its
mutation and polluted
water.
We agreed Britain Canyons of your grant for more
proof of damage to human
arteries increased blood pressure link
to some contamination.
But one of our available funds are no earmarks
aboard for the rick Gary the
ecological study.
Alive or dead this specimen
begs for further study. Don't
you agree? Dr. James?
I think the possibilities are endless
something like this could lead us to the
basic structure of life itself
even reveal some shift in The evolutionary
process that can create something
half man half sea creature
John won't you at
least give it consideration?
I'm sorry Ricardo.
I got on money somewhere else
Rick. I believe me. I
hope you succeed.
Howdy doc, you gotta be steep
Dodge boy. Have I heard about you?
Susan Fest Wranglers stuntman animal
trainer runs.
She didn't leave too much out about you. Either back.
That'll be the best sales pitch. I ever got on the telephone
if you got to be Einstein and that's all fell
all rolled up into one. Well, she filled me in a bit
about Johnny Caruso to well
Caruso needs to know is that there may be a
circus attraction in it. What circus
I look JC is no scientist.
I mean, he's won everything from this animal farm to us
traveling Sideshow out of Coney
Island anytime. He
bankrolled.
He wants to know what's in it for him satisfaction of
knowing you supporting a worthwhile
scientific field trip. She don't
Savvy that that man
fish talking spark him
man fish to
above the next Carney man. He wants to know what
the attraction is.
That's about the size of it.
Just the other night on TV. I show one of them will
clicks about an eighth time in
the Empire State Building the
whole damn Army chase me. He
kept swatting them airplanes buzzing
around it. Like they were blue-tailed flies
taking Jessie.
All right. Dogs is the James boys.
How about a Johnny TV?
Tell me.
Thank you partner.
Sunday's keeps right up with us.
How much worth it. I guess it all the way out
here. I've been over better roads
chasing wild kangaroos in Austin
country.
Look
Henry takes
probably be reception committee waiting
for an excuse.
We're almost there - will announce ourselves
place looks deserted. I don't
understand.
Hello.
mord
well
Carlos anybody hear my voice
mart mart
I've got lots of matches for you.
Maybe they went to an air-cooled movie.
some animal Maybe
Good, we've been human.
Had to be more than one to do this.
Is he the only one you left here?
Almost Stein and Carlos.
Where's Susan?
What are you doing?
Never even saw what happened. Rick had gone
into town to check on some of our control
cases Carlos took off to visit his
parents. We'd found a second squared
Monroe Was preparing it for
dissection Senor. I am every
K. I'll be happy if the
village of Tessa
It's not funny be two three miles.
We could bury your Amigo in our church our
senior if you win. Thank you.
We've already taken care of it. May
I see where it happened? Yes, of
course.
They tell me there's some sort of superstition about half
man half sea serpent with many
arms, but no one yet has
seen its annual
for my grandmother. I have heard about these
strange creatures.
He is now called me of winner.
The boy he draws were mixed things of wouldn't
play to sell them in the market
place under tonight. I sound like
the moon. My grandmother says,
where did you grandmother? Say the strange creature might be found.
I could lead you there Amigo saying
your according to his grandmother is
Pottery was taken by such a
creature. This happened
long.
His grandmother was a woman with a
big imagination.
It is fellow no never we met I just
started. He says he won't go
as for myself. I agree with him. If I were used in you ever
forget about I will
show you the place of which my
grandmother told me the authority
from the top of the hill. You can see what it is.
Well, Rick.
And on the way, it better be
Wicked first. I don't think it's
impossible mind. If we borrow these
scandals carry the water.
Okay? No be a
spoiler. This is like an Arab Village.
Beyond is in order Lake
beyond that still another all connected
like
Hannah chain, what is flow
from one to the other down from the scene?
But it is here. My grandmother's
did they leave?
Well, let's break happened follow those
beads.
tired, baby
It is better we go on before I
kissed our
IQ
in focus.
I'm not.
wisdom really offend you
music hath charms
to soothe the Savage breast
Let's hope those demons were after are aware of it.
The place like this would be going to think of God and creation.
The question is have we improved any
since creation
sure
to make mistakes. We also
make progress some good
some bad. It's all part of man's
Journey young people
underneath all that hair and you vote.
They know what it's about. They don't were doing
earth water.
Everything that grows. How do you
fit in Pickering?
I don't Savvy all that talk about us poisoning the
Earth. Well, the kids are my biology class must have
learned something. They're busy recycling everything
from Coke bottles plastic
containers. When you bring them the
arguments Professor me.
I'm going to bring him a half man half
sea serpent see who
they cheer harder for.
The water in this Lake test about the same for
radioactivity as we found in the village what
happens you drink enough of it turn
into a mutant.
Well, you remember the baby's born explainers
or without eyes or mouth after Hiroshima
had was Japan, you know Village it was
like that.
Air and water are everywhere you load them with
such poison. You are likely to
have deformity like the little
squid was sold with the eye.
You're going to tell me that killed your
Amigo mutation can be a hundred
times larger than normal. You'll find me
that giant squid doc.
We'll all get rich right Stevie
boy.
We're about ready to move on. We'll follow the shoreline
longest Chain of Lakes. He the way David of
Drury.
Will that be the beetle?
You have talent of you. Could I see you?
I know.
Someday, maybe I take lessons in
your squares in your more
Maya Square. Only teacher had a mug somebody,
okay?
Only teach you how to be like all the others.
Okay.
Got voting on am looking for anymore me and
Stevie. No. All right. Yeah, I
bet scientist the county
operator and one Expedition come one come
all.
You really expect to find anything in that drop of
bilge. Don't bother the scientist.
Your turn will come when we find it Cowboy whatever we're looking
for.
And then you can saddle break up.
like having watched
seen you like this before
it's as though you were listening to something.
What is it you do here?
whispering
Fine,
and I want
to run yet. I can't.
Don't you ever sleep?
What's biting you lately?
I don't know.
I got a hunch. We're coming up empty this
trip.
as my grandmother said it would be
in place of meeting. I saw
many of them here calling to one another.
It's gone.
First thing in the morning
so that camp around here.
Bring up the equipment.
The same thing are equal to each other.
What are you talking about? We have the
little creature. We could have
dissected them more like an
autopsy with those eyes looking up at
you.
Octopod species jellyfish
or kin to the mutants and were born in Hiroshima. That's a
mighty sentimental notion for a
scientist knows what Atomic radiation
is capable of creating.
Or distorting
you come I find more them
keep an eye on will be back soon.
Woman's Place is in the kitchen.
Hey.
I think I better keep an eye on her.
Johnny
And you never saw it.
I couldn't turn around. I tried to
but it held me like a nest of snakes
Carlos got a good look at it.
Take some of this Johnny.
Rick the specimen canister we left on
the table is gone.
The killer must have taken it.
I do not mean to frighten you seen your
toes always is dead. I am
sorry for Carlos. It is a like the
man who has killed him and I
believe there exists a sea
creature with the Arms of an octopus who walks on
the earth like a man
because I have seen him.
Natural habitat
long as it keeps out of mind. If you didn't have
your wrestling could like that to the ground
kind of equalize and guns.
The hell did it expect to find here anyway.
squeeze in the canister excited
You trying to tell me that?
There's some kind of communication
between what was in that Cannon and
that monster.
We found the canister What's Happening Here?
What part of a colorable
solve this time to get
the hell out while we can did you
hit him Johnny? It's going to take more than a couple
of shots to bring that thing down.
Really Fresh Mark the lead to the
lake. It will follow him Johnny's
right we make this last
It's counter we get out right on
his tail nailing this time. You
stay W in your
twenties. Somebody has to look after the scenery.
An extra gun under the driver seat, but I keep it handy.
Be careful.
cut the motor
that Direction
slow very slow
Cut the light.
How long would
it take it easy boy?
Try the motor again, Steve.
Johnny yeah.
If it's any consolation to you, it
wasn't the thing that was shooting.
Davida
David
Daddy, though.
David oh
I was a kid -
well he ought to know better.
The gun you can go on Rick.
There it is.
No.
Don't let him get near the water see
his face. He doesn't like that light keep
pressing it Steve. I've got an idea.
You are beautiful sight to be holding me, though.
Remind me to tell you the story of David and
Goliath.
You make it back. I don't know
they have been out of the water too long as you're
watching. How do you control
is pumped full of tranquilizers?
And if worse comes to worst, we've always got these iced tea.
Okay, we get out now.
Okay, why not?
It's my bankroll and I say we go
back we must do some studies in its
natural habitat.
Well don't count on me.
Never caught you haven't had any sleep
all night for that was me and the
kids take turns looking after our friend
here. All right.
Sleep at the post.
I'll be shot at Sunrise.
I must say she was out of your courage in the face of the
enemy inspiring.
I never thought of him.
the Beast
The old fairy tale about the lonely Beach
wanted was to be loved
the long.
Isn't that what we all
what?
Smells good after the rain
sounds of the Unseen World.
I wonder about the
language.
so lonely, so
maybe what sounds like
pain to us just the opposite to
them.
Up. There's the infant Eternal.
We Mortals feel we can
and must explain but we don't try
to explain other things like
attention so I get to my gun.
There was no warning all of a sudden he was Poppin
bellowing you wouldn't believe that unless you've
been here. He actually
got to it. We could have gone into
the brush or the lake.
Not with all those
Molotov cocktails to
protectors.
You got your matches wet boy. The rain
revived him. I couldn't help it.
Now maybe you'll agree The Safaris over.
Let's make tracks doc. We can't give
up so close to a significant fine.
plea
The way I see it JC.
just in our decision to make
okay.
You read the place it last place. You would go and
hides in your toilet with
electrodes narrow
on its way from the scene.
Right cap soon as it's light.
You had us some horses. We might get around it.
Well, whatever put it there doesn't want to
saute.
Roman feeding it toolbox if we can pull
this behind.
start
Let it out.
Right again,
what back this thing out of here
quickly. I'll be outside of
the veto.
Let me
know.
Where are you.
David are you all right?
He I'd follow him here. I like
tomorrow. We're going back
what I see him. It's no fair.
You come so far for NADA finished.
Then I go.
Democratic Expedition doctor all those in favor
discontinuing say I
we go
It's something we having that.
Fresh Tracks in that direction
he's been here. I'm
beginning to wonder if we're following
him or he's following
us.
dead end
Let's get the hell out of here.
Hey, Jenny.
Yeah, don't give up so
soon. I remember
movie one I've ever
submarine Pratt.
on the bottom of the ocean
the idea was
to save oxygen
not getting too excited.
He's right Johnny. You're
excited to just going to use more air.
No, they want think different.
comes quitting time
Guys in the fake submarine go home.
Well that's coming. You're not going
to see where it leaves water and
drowning for Lucky,
but there's barely room for you
Rick.
You'd be surprised what the body can compensate the place of
survival? I am smart
I go.
David oh, all right.
That's 5,000 you owe me Steve. It
says they didn't even like to quit while
I'm ahead.
Jesus
another one of those movies you saw
We'ii come out on the lake
side may be tight for senior Johnny.
Haven't you heard how the body compensates in the face of
danger Steve you follow the boy
Johnny next.
Yeah.
Yeah, but we still got that log to negotiate over here
versus here the same way
we got in will get up.
Hey don't judge me.